Force, M. F. (Manning Ferguson), 1824-1899. M. F. Force additional papers, 1845-1900 (MS Am 1862): Guide.
M. F. Force additional papers,
- II. Letters to Manning F. Force
  - Rhoades, William C. A.L.s.; Maysville, 3 Dec 1886., (353); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Royers, Emily. A.L.s.; Boscobel, 20 Mar [1865?], (354); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Scribner, W. S. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Madison, 29 May 1870., (355); 1s. (2p.) env.
    - Madison, 13 Dec 1872., (356); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Shaler, Nathaniel Southgate, 1841-1906. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Newport, 18 Feb 1874., (357); 1s. (3p.)
    - Newport, 16 Mar 1874., (358); 1s. (3p.) env.
  - Shaw, Quincy A. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Boston, 31 Oct 1870., (359); 1s. (4p.)
    - Paris, 6 Jan 1883., (360); 1s. (4p.) env.
  - Sherman, Henry. 3 A.L.s.:
    - Berkshire, 12 Mar 1871., (361); 1s. (3p.) env.
    - Berkshire, 17 Mar 1871., (362); 1s. (3p.)
    - Berkshire, 7 Jul 1871., (363); 1s. (4p.)
  - Sherman, William Tecumseh, 1820-1891. 5 A.L.s.:
    - Saint Louis, 5 Oct 1868., (364); 1s. (4p.)
    - Saint Louis, 5 Sep 1875., (365); 1s. (4p.)
    - Washington, 24 Nov 1880., (366); 1s. (4p.)
    - Washington, 19 Mar 1881., (367); 1s. (4p.)
    - Washington, 23 Mar 1881., (368); 1s. (4p.)
  - Skinner, Hillary. A.L.s.; Athens, 22 Sep 1868., (369); 1s. (3p.) env.
  - Skinner, Louisa S. A.L.s.; London, 14 Jul 1868., (370); 1s. (4p.)
  - Slicer, I. S. A.L.s.; St. Joseph, 19 May 1872., (371); 1s. (2p.)
  - Smith, Thomas Kilby, 1820-1887. A.L.s.; Philadelphia, 8 Apr 1881., (372); 1s. (3p.) env.
  - Somers, F. S. A.L.s.; Washington, 8 Feb 1872., (373); 2s. (3p.) env.
    On the back is an MS. note in the hand of Manning F. Force; [n.p., n.d.]
  - Speker, P. W. A.L.s.; [Boltkues?] 12 Apr 1878., (374); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Strong, George Augustus, 1832-1912. 2 A.L.s.:
    - [Garnhin?] 23 May 1871., (375); 1s. (4p.) env.
    - [Garnhin?] 13 Jun 1871., (376); 1s. (4p.)
  - Sullivan, John Clyde. 3 A.L.s.:
    - Washington, 23 Mar 1869., (377); 1s. (2p.)
    - Washington, 6 Jan 1871., (378); 1s. (4p.) env.
    - Washington, 10 Dec 1871., (379); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Talbot, Thomas Hammond, 1823- A.L.s.; Washington, 18 Sep 1871., (380); 1s. (1p.) env.
    Written for Alexander Johnston.
  - Taylor, [Daniel] M. A.L.s.; Fort Garland, 19 Aug 1883., (381); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Thomas, Griffin J. A.L.s.; Berlin, 23 Dec 1872., (382); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Thurman, Allen Granberry, 1813-1895. T.L.s.; Columbus, 7 Aug 1886., (383); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Torrey, H. W. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Cambridge, 2 Dec 1874., (384); 1s. (3p.)
      With an MS. note (in the hand of [ ] Loving); [n.p., n.d.] 1s. (1p.)
    - Cambridge, 31 Jan [n.d.], (385); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Waddell, John. A.L.s.; Mt. Vernon, 27 Mar 1871., (386); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Waddell, William L. A.L.s.; Mt. Vernon, 9 Mar 1883., (387); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Waite, Morrison Remick, 1816-1888. A.L.s.; Burnet House, 16 Jan [n.d.], (388); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Walker, James Bryant. A.L.s.; Cincinnati, 6 Jul 1871., (389); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Walker, Russell. A.L.s.; Yellow Springs, 24 Feb 1877., (390); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Ware, William Robert, 1832-1915. A.L.s.; Boston, 19 Jun 1871., (391); 1s. (4p.) env.
    Concerning the election of overseers of Harvard College.
  - Weatherby, P. A.L.s.; El Paso, 1 May 1876., (392); 2s. (3p.) env.
  - Webb, Almon D. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Warren, 16 May 1866., (393); 1s. (1p.)
    - same, 21 Jun 1866., (394); 1s. (3p.)
  - White, William. 3 A.L.s.:
    - Columbus, 27 Mar [1871?], (395); 1s. (3p.)
    - Springfield, 28 Jul [1871?], (396); 1s. (2p.)
    - Columbus, 11 Nov 1882., (397); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Whittlesey, Charles, 1808-1886. 6 A.L.s.:
    - Cleveland, 16 Nov 1870., (398); 1s. (1p.)
    - same, 25 Nov 1870., (399); 1s. (1p.)
    - same, 12 Dec 1870., (400); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 26 Dec 1870., (401); 2s. (2p.) env.
    - same, 5 Apr 1872., (402); 2s. (2p.)
    - same, 5 Nov 1884., (403); 1s. (4p.)
  - Wicker, S. A.L.s.; Willshire, 12 Mar 1882., (404); 1s. (3p.) env.
  - Williams, Alma G. A.L.s.; Vicksburg, 8 Mar 1866., (405); 1s. (2p.)
  - Williams, William H. 4 A.L.s.:
    - Vicksburg, 7 Mar 1866., (406); 1s. (4p.) env.
    - Washington, [8 Jun 1866?], (407); 1s. (1p.)
      Includes a letter (signed) from Alma G. Williams to Manning F. Force; Washington, 8 Jun 1866. 1s. (2p.)
    - Leavenworth, 18 Dec 1871., (408); 1s. (2p.)
    - same, 8 Jan 1872., (409); 1s. (3p.)
  - Yade, Yehr. 2 A.L.s.:
    - Philadelphia, 1 May 1877., (410); 1s. (1p.) env.
    - Christiania, 10 Jul 1877., (411); 1s. (3p.) env.
  - Young, Phillip W. A.L.s.; Anna, 7 Feb 1873., (412); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Young, Thomas L. A.L.s.; Columbus, 20 Dec 1877., (413); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Youngblue, Jesse R. A.L.s.; Sarahsville, 28 Apr 1873., (414); 1s. (1p.) env.
  - Ziegler, George M. 3 A.L.s.:
    - Meridian, 20 Dec 1865., (415); 1s. (2p.)
    - Ashwood Landing, 12 Jul 1866., (416); 1s. (2p.)
    - Wilmington, 12 Jan 1886., (417); 2s. (2p.) env.
- III. Other letters
  - Bliss, Eugene Frederick, 1836- T.L.s. to Horton C. Force; Cincinnati, 23 May 1899., (418); 2s. (2p.)
  - Force, Horton C. A.L.s. to Eugene F. Bliss; Erie County, 19 May 1899., (419); 1s. (1p.)
  - Kebler, John. A.L.s. to Peter Force; Cincinnati, 3 Sep 1861., (420); 1s. (2p.)
  - Kebler, John. A.L.s. (fragment) to [ ]; [n.p.] 25 Mar 1863., (421); 1s. (2p.)
  - Quincy, Josiah, 1792-1864. A.L.s. to William Dennison; Boston, 21 Aug [1861?], (422); 1s. (2p.) env.
  - Wells, G. Wiley. A.L.s. to John B. Raymond; Holly Springs, 30 Nov 1871., (423); 1s. (1p.)
  - Wilby, Joseph. T.L.s. to Horton C. Force; Cincinnati, 31 Mar 1900., (424); 1s. (1p.)
    With an MS. list of books (unidentified hand); [n.p., n.d.] 4s. (4p.) and an MS. list of military articles belonging to Manning F. Force ( in the hand of Horton C. Force); [n.p., n.d.] 1s. (1p.)
  - Wulsin, Drausin. T.L.s. to Horton C. Force; Cincinnati, 7 Mar 1900., (425); 1s. (1p.)
- IV. Manuscripts
  - Academia de la Historia, Madrid. [Diploma] MS.D. (unidentified hand, signed by Pedro de Madrazo); Madrid, 13 Mar 1886., (426); 1s. (1p.)
  - Force, Manning Ferguson, 1824-1899. [Diaries] A.MS.; [v.p.] 1861, 1863-1866. 5v., (427)
  - Force, Manning Ferguson, 1824-1899. [General Sherman's special field order No. 22] A.MS.; [n.p., n.d.], (428); 1s. (1p.)
    Passage copied from General and Field Orders. Campaign of the Armies of the Tennessee, Ohio and Cumberland..., St. Louis, 1865. pp. 190-191.
  - Force, Manning Ferguson, 1824-1899. A Peep at Europe. A.MS.; [n.p., n.d.], (429); 12s. (24p.)
  - Literary Club, Cincinnati. In Memory of Manning F. Force. TS. (signed by G.S. Sykes); Cincinnati, 27 May 1899., (430); 7s. (7p.)
    Also signed by John W. Herron, [ ] Ladle,; Herbert Lenney,; Hiram D. Peck, and Thornton M. [ ].
  - [unidentified] Sequel of the "Kearsarge's" Career. MS. (unsigned, unidentified hand); [n.p., Apr 1895?], (431); 1s. (2p.)
- V. Miscellany
  - [Civil War photographs] 75 photographs of Civil War soldiers, mostly men of the 20th Ohio Volunteers; [v.p., ca. 1862], (432)
  - [Family portraits] 8 photographs of Manning F. Force and various members of his family; [v.p., v.d.], (433)
  - [Miscellaneous manuscripts], (434); 1 folder.
  - [Miscellaneous printed material (maps, offsets, etc.)], (435); 1 box.